# Zoran Stepanoski

#### Electrical engineer for computer technology

C

+381605183892



zstepanoski@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/zoran-stepanoski-788567b/



https://zoranstepanoski-prof-website.fly.dev/



17. Oktobra 14/43, 11300 Smederevo, Republic of Serbia

# Work experience

# Technical Consultant/ Software Engineer

## DataHub, Smederevo

October 2023. - current

- Development of completely new application for windows and android mobile app from the scratch for solving the problem of school timetables.
- ISB (Information system for safety at work):

Maintaining of existing functionalities and create a new one in Web based application. Development of functions, stored procedures, views, triggers and other development of new database functionalities. Creating simple ETL services in Python for integration between existing ERP database with ISB database.

# Freelancer Software Developer

# Želvoz doo, Smederevo - plant for railway vehicles maintenance

March 2023 - Jun 2023. (3 months)

- Planning the work lists for tomorrow's working day depending on the available workforce. The goal of this project was to create a new module which would enable the head of the organizational unit to organize and plan what are the work duties for tomorrow and the assignment of employees to the appropriate tasks using textual UI.

# Senior Oracle PL/SQL developer

## IGT doo, Beograd

April 2022 - Dec. 2022

Maintaining existing procedures, functions, views, triggers and developing new database functionalities for sports betting software. My main task was to upgrade and optimize existing PL/SQL procedures and functions, Queries in materialized and classical views.

## Software development engineer

## 2D Soft doo, Novi Sad

May 2021 - April 2022

Design, development, implementation and maintenance of POS solutions for catering businesses.

- POS Project in Montenegro, adjustments of existing POS software and creating new functionalities for new law regulations
- POS Project in Serbia, adjustments of existing POS software and creating new functionalities for new law regulations (eFiscalization)

## Software development engineer

## Gencom software - Belgium based company with office in Smederevo

Feb. 2013 - Apr. 2021

Design, development, implementation and maintenance of ERP solutions for the fashion industry - Delphi XE4, XE7 (and later Delphi 10) implementing FireMonkey framework for developing cross-platform client applications, VCL, Oracle 11g and 12c, PL/SQL, open-source PL/JSON (REST/JSON), VSS and Git (Tortoise).

- Variety of different apps for Android and iOS smartphones.
- ERP solution:
  - POS (Point of Sales) application for clothing and footwear stores through which fiscal invoices are printed, tracking stocks, orders or shipping goods, order goods through online stores and etc.
  - FashPlus ERP solution for clothing and footwear sales companies
  - o FinadWin financial package
  - o FashMaker ERP solution for production processes optimization
- Omnichannel: Development of REST/JSON based Oracle 12c APIs using open-source PL/JSON packages. The goal of this project was to move all business logic from client side (fat client) to the DB side (fat backend), creating REST/JSON APIs callable from the any type of client side (iOS, Android, Web-sites, desktop application) using POS (Point of Sales) functionalities. The whole system consists of Oracle DB, Windows API gateway service (security and load balancing) and clients apps. The only purpose of Windows API gateway service was to verify and forward REST/JSON requests to the stored procedure in Oracle DB send back the results in JSON format. There is also support for HTTPS communication protocol implemented.
- Oracle BI, creating and optimizing SQL queries for reporting and business analytics purposes.

# Software development engineer

## OtaCo Engineering-Smederevo

Dec. 2011 - Feb. 2013

Member of the team for design, development and implementation of level 2 applications for real-time monitoring and control of refueling at the Oil Tanking fuel depot in Terneuzen, Netherlands - Visual Studio 2010, C#, WCF, WPF (XAML), OPC DA.

I would also like to point out the project where I had to write cross compiler which was translating some custom-made language into C-like programming language – regular expressions and recursion calls to break the syntax of custom-made language into tokens for translating to C.

#### Information architect

## United States Steel Corporation-Smederevo

Feb. 2009 - Nov. 2011

I was responsible for the administration of Oracle Application Servers, providing support to the software development team in solving JAVA software problems, code optimization, testing and integration of solutions using Oracle development tools.

On this position I was responsible to check the health of Oracle DB and application servers HW and SW.

#### **ERP** consultant

## United States Steel Corporation HQ - Pittsburgh, USA

Feb. 2007 - Jan. 2009

I was the member of the international team as an ERP consultant. This experience helped me understand how important ERP solutions are for the successful operation of a large company and allowed me to access and learn about the latest technologies such as Oracle SOA and Oracle Fusion Middleware tools (BPEL / OSB) which were mostly used as ETL tools. Although they were not primarily designed as ETL tools, I learned workflows, transformations using XSLT and handling different types of sources and destinations such as CSV files, variety of databases, FTP servers and shared folders. I participated in all phases of the development of the software solution for connecting the legacy systems with the new information system in the U.S. Steel Corporation, such as developing, testing, documenting and implementing software solutions. BPEL and ESB (later OSB) were used for creating web services for orchestrating business processes and service mediation and transformation. Web services were deployed and running on dedicated Oracle Application Server. Technology used: SOAP/WSDL, Oracle SOA Fusion Middleware (BPEL – Business Process Executional Language, OSB – Oracle Service Bus)

#### Team leader

## United States Steel Corporation - Smederevo

Dec. 2003 - Jan. 2007

I was leader of a team of experienced programmers who have been involved in the design and development of level 2 software for production monitoring on a continuous casting machine in a steel making plant using data acquisition from variety of PLCs and as a part of process control group (SSL2, SSL3 projects, Continuous casting machine – Realtime measuring slab lengths).

## Leading software developer

## Milan Blagojević AD - Smederevo

Jan. 2001 - Nov. 2003

At the position of a leading programmer, I was responsible for maintenance of existing and developing of new financial business system modules.

# Software Developer

#### Freelancer

Dec. 1991 - Jan 2003. (12 years 2 months)

- Design and development of an application for creating school timetables for primary schools using SA algorithm
- Graphical representation of power states for 10/0.4KV, 35/10KV and 110/35KV energetic network in Electric power plant of Serbia (EPS), Smederevo branch

#### **Skills**

#### Programing languages:

- DELPHI (7, 2007, XE4, XE7, 10, FireMonkey, VCL): over 15 years
- SQL, PL/SQL using Oracle and Allround Automations SQL Developer, SQL\*Plus and TOAD: over 10 years
- C#, MS Visual Studio 2010 (WCF, WPF): over 3 years
- Java using Oracle JDeveloper and IntelliJ IDE: over 3 years
- C/C++ using gcc: over 2 years

#### Databases:

- Oracle (10g, 11g, 12c): over 10 years
- PostgreSQL: over 6 yearsInformix i4gl: over 3 years
- MS SQL: Over 1 year

Source safe and version control:

- Visual Source Safe
- · Git using Mercurial
- GitHub

#### Other technologies:

- REST/JSON, open-source PL/JSON: over 6 years
- SOAP/WSDL: over 6 years
- Windows services development: over 6 years
- Web services using Oracle Fusion Middleware (SOA Suite BPEL for orchestrating business processes, OSB for service mediation and transformation): over 2 years
- JHipster, Angular, HTML, Typescript, Jasper, H2 database: over 2 years
- Oracle BI: over 1 year

#### Operating systems:

- MS Windows: over 30 years
- SCO UNIX, Rad Hat Linux: over 10 years

#### Trainings:

- Oracle Application Server 10g R2: Administration I, II
- Oracle SOA Suite 10g: Service Orchestration Ed 1
- SIMATIC ST7 PRO 1
- Informatica ETLShort about me

#### **Education**

1996-1999

College of Electrical Engineering, Belgrade - Electrical engineer for computer science where I gained an Associate degree in Information technologies

1991-1996

Faculty of Electrical Engineering, Computer and Information technologies, Belgrade - 3<sup>rd</sup> year but never finished 1987-1991

Technical high school 'Milentije Popović', Smederevo - Mathematical and programming associate

#### **Summary**

I have been a professional in the IT sector for more than 20 years and I have experience in various aspects of information technology which includes database design and development as well as application software development, engineering, consulting and team management. I gained this experience by working on various projects, mostly in the field of metal production and processing. In recent years, I have also been engaged in developing ERP solutions for the fashion industry and POS (Point of Sales) solutions.

I also have experience in implementing large ERP systems, which includes two years of participation in an international ERP system implementation team for the U.S. Steel Corporation HO in Pittsburgh, USA.

As a teenager, I was interested in computer graphics, artificial intelligence, programming and everything else related to computers and technology, and in high school I participated in a summer camp at the Petnica Research Center as a talented programmer.

Currently, I am most interested in the development and implementation of real-time production monitoring systems, digital electronics and artificial intelligence (neural networks and algorithms for solving optimization NP-Hard problems) and new technologies like GoLang, Python, JHipster, Typescript and other web-based technologies which I am eager to learn.

After I graduated from high school in 1991, I enrolled in Faculty of Electrical Engineering in Belgrade, which I had to leave in 1996 at the 3<sup>rd</sup> year, after which I transferred to the College of Electrical Engineering in Belgrade, where I became advanced student in 1999 and where I graduated after mandatory military service and gained a college associate degree. I am passionate about technology and continuous learning.

#### Languages

English – Fluent in writing, reading and speaking (10 years of education in school + 2 years in USA everyday conversation + 8 years in everyday conversation with Belgium colleagues).

More about me on my Website - https://zoranstepanoski-prof-website.fly.dev/